A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1956
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1956
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.634
This collection consists of 9,600 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to the library. Date unknown.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
There is also an architectural drawing of Master Site Plan for the western portion of University of Virginia.
Contents List
- General Files, 1956
  - "A - Am" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 1)
  - "An - Az" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 1)
  - Admissions 1956 (Box 1)
  - Air Force 1956 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Association 1956 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Fund 1956 (Box 1)
  - American Council on Education 1956 (Box 1)
  - Annual Reports 1956 (Box 1)
  - Applications for Positions - "A" 1956 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "B" 1956 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "C" 1956 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "D" 1956 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "E" 1956 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "F" 1956 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "G" 1956 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "H" 1956 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "I" (folder empty) 1956 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "J" 1956 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "K" 1956 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "L" 1956 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "M" 1956 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "N" 1956 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "O" 1956 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "P" 1956 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "Q" (folder empty) 1956 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "R" 1956 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "S" 1956 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "T" 1956 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "U" (folder empty) 1956 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "V" (folder empty) 1956 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "W" 1956 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "X - Y - Z" (folder empty) 1956 (Box 2)
  - Architecture 1956 (Box 2)
  - Army - General 1956 (Box 2)
  - Army - ROTC 1956 (Box 2)
  - Army - Judge Advocate General's (J.A.G.) School 1956 (Box 2)
  - Art 1956 (Box 2)
  - Art Commission 1956 (Box 2)
  - Association of American Colleges 1956 (Box 2)
  - Association of American Universities 1956 (Box 2)
  - Association of Governing Boards of State Universities 1956 (Box 2)
  - Association of Land-Grant Colleges 1956 (Box 3)
  - Association of Virginia Colleges 1956 (Box 3)
  - Astronomy 1956 (Box 3)
  - Athletics: January - June 1956 (Box 3)
  - Athletics: July - December 1956 (Box 3)
  - Athletics: Commonwealth Day 1956 (Box 3)
  - Athletics - NCAA 1956 (Box 3)
  - Auditor of Public Accounts 1956 (Box 3)
  - "Ba - Bl" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 4)
  - "Bm - Bz" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 4)
  - Bibliographical Society 1956 (Box 4)
  - Biology 1956 (Box 4)
  - Biology - Mountain Lake 1956 (Box 4)
  - Blandy Farm 1956 (Box 4)
  - Buildings and Grounds 1956 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - General 1956 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - Architects and Engineers (folder empty) 1956 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - Children's Rehabilitation Center 1956 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - Contracts 1956 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - J.A.G. Dormitory 1956 (Box 5)
  - Building Program - Life Science Building 1956 (Box 5)
  - Building Program - Medical Buildings 1956 (Box 5)
  - Building Program - Naval Armory 1956 (Box 5)
  - Building Program - Northern Virginia 1956 (Box 5)
  - Building Program - Piedmont 1956 (Box 5)
  - Building Program - Power Plant and Heating Main 1956 (Box 5)
  - Building Program - Student Activities Building 1956 (Box 5)
  - Bureau of Population and Economic Research 1956 (Box 5)
  - Bureau of Public Administration 1956 (Box 5)
  - Bursar: January - June 1956 (Box 5)
  - Bursar: July - December 1956 (Box 5)
  - Business Administration, Graduate School of: January - June 1956 (Box 6)
  - Business Administration, Graduate School of: July - December 1956 (Box 6)
  - Byrd, Senator Harry F. 1956 (Box 6)
  - "Ca - Ck" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 6)
  - "Cl - Cz" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 6)
  - Carnegie Foundation 1956 (Box 6)
  - Catalogues 1956 (Box 6)
  - Cavalier Daily 1956 (Box 6)
  - Chemistry 1956 (Box 6)
  - Chemistry - John Lee Pratt Trace Analysis Laboratory 1956 (Box 6)
  - Civilian Defense 1956 (Box 6)
  - Classics 1956 (Box 7)
  - Clinch Valley College Building Program 1956 (Box 7)
  - Clippings - General 1956 (Box 7)
  - Clippings - Segregation 1956 (Box 7)
  - College of Arts and Sciences 1956 (Box 7)
  - Commerce, McIntire Undergraduate School 1956 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Accounts (folder empty) 1956 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Advanced Standing for Exceptional Students (folder empty) 1956 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Administrative Policy of the Hospital (folder empty) 1956 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Algernon Sydney Sullivan Award (folder empty) 1956 (Box 7)
  - Committee - All-University Advisory 1956 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Arboretum (O. E. White) Advisory 1956 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Art Museum (folder empty) 1956 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Atlantic Union (folder empty) 1956 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Athletic 1956 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Balch Estate (folder empty) 1956 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Blandy Farm 1956 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Board 1956 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Calendar (folder empty) 1956 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Catalogue 1956 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Cemetery 1956 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Chapel 1956 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Clinch Valley College Building 1956 (Box 7)
  - Committee - College, Capacity of 1956 (Box 7)
  - Committee - College Reorganization (folder empty) 1956 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Contractual Relations 1956 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Education, Dean of 1956 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Educational Program for Special Training of Handicapped Children (folder empty) 1956 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Engineering Experiment Station Advisory Council 1956 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Extension (folder empty) 1956 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Faculty Health Plan 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Fellowships Award (folder empty) 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Fire Protection (folder empty) 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Food Services and Housing 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Foreign Affairs Advisory 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Fraternity 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Graduate 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Graduate School of Business Administration 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Hospital Architectural Advisory 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Institute for Research in the Social Sciences Council (folder empty) 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Jefferson Celebration 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Lectures (Page-Barbour and J. W. Richard) (folder empty) 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Lectures (Special) (folder empty) 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Library 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Life Science Building Plan 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Lower Division 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - McIntire Undergraduate School of Commerce (folder empty) 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Mary Washington College (folder empty) 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - McConnell Award 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Medical Board of the Hospital (folder empty) 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Mountain Lake Biological Station (folder empty) 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Movie of the University 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Nuclear Advisory 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Nursing School Advisory (folder empty) 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Nursing Work Study 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Patents 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Power Plant (folder empty) 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - President's Committee on Education Beyond the High School 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Presidents' Council 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Processions (folder empty) 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Professorships, Special Honor 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Public Occasions 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Research 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Rhodes Scholarship (folder empty) 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Richmond Area University Center Research Council (folder empty) 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Rushton Seminars 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Schedule and Classroom Assignments (folder empty) 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Scholarships, Loans, and Employment (folder empty) 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Science Education (folder empty) 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Stokes, W. E. (folder empty) 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Student Activities 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Student Activities Building - Decorating and Furnishing 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Student Union 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Summer Session (folder empty) 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Summer Session Degrees (College) (folder empty) 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Summer Session Degrees (Graduate) (folder empty) 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Traffic Control 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Tree 1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Virginia Quarterly Review1956 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Virginia Status of University Students 1956 (Box 8)
  - Comptroller 1956 (Box 9)
  - Council of Southern Universities 1956 (Box 9)
  - Council of State Governments 1956 (Box 9)
  - "D" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 9)
  - Davis, W. H. 1956 (Box 9)
  - "E" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 9)
  - Economics 1956 (Box 9)
  - Education 1956 (Box 9)
  - Endowment - Alumni Board of Trustees 1956 (Box 10)
  - Endowment - Contingent Fund 1956 (Box 10)
  - Engineering 1956 (Box 10)
  - English 1956 (Box 10)
  - Enrollment 1956 (Box 10)
  - Extension Division: January - June 1956 (Box 10)
  - Extension Division: July - December 1956 (Box 10)
  - Extension Division - Northern Division 1956 (Box 11)
  - Extension Division - Richmond 1956 (Box 11)
  - Extension Division - Southwest Virginia 1956 (Box 11)
  - "F" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 11)
  - Faculty 1956 (Box 11)
  - Fraternities 1956 (Box 12)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 12)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Bayly-Tiffany (folder empty) 1956 (Box 12)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Ford Foundation 1956 (Box 12)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Fulbright 1956 (Box 12)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Rhodes 1956 (Box 12)
  - Finals 1956 (Box 12)
  - Food Service 1956 (Box 12)
  - Foreign Affairs 1956 (Box 12)
  - Forestry 1956 (Box 12)
  - Founder's Day 1956 (Box 12)
  - Fund for Adult Education 1956 (Box 12)
  - "G" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 13)
  - General Education Board (folder empty) 1956 (Box 13)
  - Geography (folder empty) 1956 (Box 13)
  - Geology 1956 (Box 13)
  - Germanic Languages and Russian 1956 (Box 13)
  - Gifts and Grants 1956 (Box 13)
  - Governor's Office 1956 (Box 13)
  - Graduate School 1956 (Box 13)
  - "Ha - Hk" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 13)
  - "Hl - Hz" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 13)
  - Highway Department (State) 1956 (Box 13)
  - History 1956 (Box 14)
  - History - Madison Papers 1956 (Box 14)
  - Hildreth, W. S. 1956 (Box 14)
  - Honor System 1956 (Box 14)
  - Hospital: January - June 1956 (Box 14)
  - Hospital: July - December 1956 (Box 14)
  - Hospital - Medical Board of the Hospital 1956 (Box 14)
  - Hospital - Monthly Statistical Reports 1956 (Box 14)
  - Housing 1956 (Box 14)
  - Hull, Cordell, Foundation 1956 (Box 14)
  - "I" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 15)
  - International Association of Universities (folder empty) 1956 (Box 15)
  - Institute for Research in the Social Sciences (folder empty) 1956 (Box 15)
  - Institute of International Education 1956 (Box 15)
  - Institute of Public Affairs 1956 (Box 15)
  - Insurance 1956 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "A" 1956 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "B" 1956 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "C" 1956 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "D" 1956 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "E" 1956 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "F" 1956 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "G" 1956 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "H" 1956 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "I" 1956 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "J" 1956 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "K" (folder empty) 1956 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "L" 1956 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "M" 1956 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "N" 1956 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "O" 1956 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "P" 1956 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "Q" (folder empty) 1956 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "R" 1956 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "S" 1956 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "T" 1956 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "U" 1956 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "V" 1956 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "W" 1956 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "X - Y - Z" 1956 (Box 16)
  - "J" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 16)
  - Japan Christian University 1956 (Box 16)
  - Jefferson, Thomas - Memorial Foundation 1956 (Box 16)
  - Jefferson, Thomas - Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 16)
  - "K" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 16)
  - "L" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 17)
  - Law School 1956 (Box 17)
  - Lectures - General 1956 (Box 17)
  - Lectures - Page-Barbour 1956 (Box 17)
  - Lectures - Richard 1956 (Box 17)
  - Legal Matters 1956 (Box 17)
  - Legislative Program 1956 (Box 17)
  - Library 1956 (Box 17)
  - "Mc" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 17)
  - McConnell Award 1956 (Box 17)
  - "Ma - Me" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 18)
  - "Mi - Mz" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 18)
  - Madison Hall 1956 (Box 18)
  - Marine Corps 1956 (Box 18)
  - Mary Washington College - Alvey, Dean 1956 (Box 18)
  - Mary Washington College - Budget 1956 (Box 18)
  - Mary Washington College - Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 18)
  - Mary Washington College - Simpson, President 1956 (Box 18)
  - Mary Washington College - Mr. Woodward 1956 (Box 18)
  - Mathematics 1956 (Box 18)
  - Medicine, School of 1956 (Box 18)
  - Military (Miscellaneous) (folder empty) 1956 (Box 19)
  - Music 1956 (Box 19)
  - "N" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 19)
  - National Association of State Universities 1956 (Box 19)
  - National Commission on Accrediting 1956 (Box 19)
  - National Education Association 1956 (Box 19)
  - National Science Foundation 1956 (Box 19)
  - Navy - General 1956 (Box 19)
  - Navy - ROTC 1956 (Box 19)
  - Nursing School 1956 (Box 19)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 19)
  - Oak Ridge 1956 (Box 19)
  - "Pa - Pe" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 20)
  - "Pf - Pz" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 20)
  - Phi Beta Kappa 1956 (Box 20)
  - Philosophy 1956 (Box 20)
  - Photographs 1956 (Box 20)
  - Physical Education 1956 (Box 20)
  - Personnel (State) 1956 (Box 20)
  - Physics 1956 (Box 20)
  - Political Science 1956 (Box 20)
  - Provost 1956 (Box 20)
  - President's Council 1956 (Box 20)
  - Psychology 1956 (Box 20)
  - Public Occasions 1956 (Box 20)
  - Purchasing Office (University) (folder empty) 1956 (Box 20)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 20)
  - Questionnaires 1956 (Box 20)
  - "R" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 21)
  - Raven Society 1956 (Box 21)
  - Recommendations 1956 (Box 21)
  - Referendum 1956 (Box 21)
  - Regional Education 1956 (Box 21)
  - Registrar 1956 (Box 21)
  - Religion 1956 (Box 21)
  - 1956 (Box 21)
  - Requisitions 1956 (Box 22)
  - Research - General 1956 (Box 22)
  - Richmond Area University Center 1956 (Box 22)
  - Rockefeller Foundation 1956 (Box 22)
  - Romance Languages 1956 (Box 22)
  - "Sa - Sl" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 22)
  - "Sm - Sz" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 22)
  - Salaries 1956 (Box 22)
  - Segregation 1956 (Box 23)
  - Senate (University) 1956 (Box 23)
  - Sigma Xi 1956 (Box 23)
  - Sociology 1956 (Box 23)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools 1956 (Box 23)
  - Southern Association of Land-Grant Colleges 1956 (Box 23)
  - Southern University Conference 1956 (Box 23)
  - Speech and Drama 1956 (Box 23)
  - Speeches and Articles 1956 (Box 23)
  - State Board of Education 1956 (Box 23)
  - State Department of Health 1956 (Box 23)
  - State University Association 1956 (Box 23)
  - Statistics 1956 (Box 23)
  - Student Affairs Office 1956 (Box 23)
  - Student Aid Office 1956 (Box 24)
  - Student Health Department 1956 (Box 24)
  - Summer Session 1956 (Box 24)
  - Surplus Property 1956 (Box 24)
  - "T" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 24)
  - Travel 1956 (Box 24)
  - Treasurer of Virginia 1956 (Box 24)
  - Treasury Department 1956 (Box 24)
  - "U" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 24)
  - United Nations 1956 (Box 24)
  - United States Department of Health, Education, and Welfare 1956 (Box 24)
  - United States Department of State 1956 (Box 25)
  - University News Service 1956 (Box 25)
  - University Press 1956 (Box 25)
  - "V" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 25)
  - Veterans (folder empty) 1956 (Box 25)
  - Virginia Academy of Science (folder empty) 1956 (Box 25)
  - Virginia Education Association 1956 (Box 25)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1956 (Box 25)
  - Visitors - Dockets and Minutes 1956 (Box 25)
  - Visitors - General Correspondence 1956 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Barksdale, A. D. 1956 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Berkeley, Norborne 1956 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Black, E. F. 1956 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Bryan, Judge Albert V. 1956 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Coxe, W. W. 1956 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Emmett, J. M. 1956 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Gravatt, J. S. 1956 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Gray, H. A., Jr. 1956 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Greear, Fred B. 1956 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Hartfield, J. 1956 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Howard, D. J. 1956 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Jones, Mrs. B. T. 1956
  - Visitors - McWane, Henry 1956 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Mears, B. W. 1956 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Martin, Dr. Walter 1956 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Pollock, Herbert 1956 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Smith, Mrs. H. M. 1956 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Smith, Howard W. 1956 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Talbott, Frank 1956 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Wheeler, Ms. Lucille 1956 (Box 27)
  - "Wa - Wh" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 27)
  - "Wi - Wz" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 27)
  - Wilson, Woodrow 1956 (Box 27)
  - Women, Dean of 1956 (Box 27)
  - "X - Y - Z" Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 27)